Mss.Rec.29 Mss.Rec.29
American Philosophical Society
Winnebago Texts
1959
Mss.Rec.29
American Philosophical Society
14.0 Reel(s)
Blackhawk, Andrew
Fraenkel, Gerd
Radin, Paul, 1883-1959
Smoke, Elias James
Stacy, Stella
Thundercloud, Adam
Whiterabbit, Mitchell
Indians of North America--Wisconsin--Wars; Menominee Indians--History; Prophets; Sound recordings; Translating and interpreting; Winnebago Indians--Folklore; Winnebago Indians--History; Winnebago Indians--Religion; Winnebago Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Winnebago Indians--Social life and customs; Winnebago language--Glossaries, vocabularies, etc.; Winnebago language--Texts; Winnebago mythology
- Audio recordings
  - Songs and Stories Connected with the Medicine Dance, 1959-07-08; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:08; Blackhawk, Andrew; Fraenkel, Gerd; Thundercloud, Adam
    Scope and Contents note
    Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University.
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Sound tape reel) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
    Black River Falls (Wis.); Winnebago dance; Winnebago Indians--Music
  - Ritual Dance Music and Stories Connected with Medicine Dances for the Initiaion of Youngsters, 1959-07-08; 01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:13:02; Blackhawk, Andrew; Fraenkel, Gerd; Thundercloud, Adam
    Black River Falls (Wis.); Initiation rites; Winnebago dance; Winnebago Indians--Music; Winnebago Indians--Rites and ceremonies
  - War of Indian tribes against white soldiers, 1959-07-11; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:16; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 523.1.
    Black River Falls (Wis.); Indians of North America--Wisconsin--Wars; Winnebago Indians--History; Winnebago Indians--Wars; Winnebago language--Texts
  - The red man's plaint against the white man about white supremacy, 1959-07-11; 02-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:58; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 523.3.
    Black River Falls (Wis.); Whites--Wisconsin--Relations with Indians; Winnebago Indians--History; Winnebago language--Texts
  - A story about red-white rivalry and the background of an arrest, 1959-07-11; 02-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:00; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 523.5-7.
    Arrest; Black River Falls (Wis.); Whites--Wisconsin--Relations with Indians; Winnebago Indians--History; Winnebago language--Texts
  - A woman who is going to stop the war, 1959-07-11; 02-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:22; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 525.9-10.
    Black River Falls (Wis.); Winnebago Indians--History; Winnebago Indians--Wars; Winnebago language--Texts; Winnebago women; Women and war
  - Two boys and a boat, 1959-07-12; 02-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:16; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 526.1.
    Black River Falls (Wis.); Winnebago language--Texts
  - More about the conversation between the captain and the prisoners, 1959-07-12; 02-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:05; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 526.2.
    Black River Falls (Wis.); Prisoners; Winnebago Indians--History; Winnebago language--Texts
  - Prisoner's story and song; A girl saved by a couple, 1959-07-12; 02-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:10; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's programs 526.3 and 526.6
  - A man accused of untrue predictions, 1959-07-12; 02-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:07; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 526.5.
  - The red man's plaint about the white man's control of the country, 1959-07-12; 02-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:00; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 526.6.
  - A drunk man and his deeds, 1959-07-12; 02-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:04; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 526.8.
    Alcoholics; Black River Falls (Wis.); Winnebago language--Texts
  - Winnebagos go to see the prophet Shawanoworak, 1959-07-12; 02-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:16; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 526.9, which continues on 528.2. See Related Recording.
    Black River Falls (Wis.); Prophets; Winnebago Indians--History; Winnebago language--Texts
  - The beginning of the Winnebago, 1959-07-12; 02-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:28; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 526.10.
    Black River Falls (Wis.); Winnebago Indians--Folklore; Winnebago Indians--History; Winnebago language--Texts
  - The sayings of an old man about his medicine bag, 1959-07-12; 02-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:35; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 526.11, which is continued on 528.5. See Related Recording.
    Black River Falls (Wis.); Winnebago Indians--Medicine; Winnebago language--Texts
  - The young boy who wanted to go war, 1959-07-12; 02-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:58; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 526.12.
    Black River Falls (Wis.); Children and war; Winnebago Indians--Wars; Winnebago language--Texts
  - The Winnebago and two other tribes pitch their winter wigwam and then proceed to a tribal meeting, 1959-07-12; 02-15; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:58; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 526.13.
    Black River Falls (Wis.); Winnebago Indians--History; Winnebago language--Texts
  - Deeds of tribes whose youngsters go to school to get an education, 1959-07-12; 02-16; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:59; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 527.2.
    Black River Falls (Wis.); Indians of North America--Wisconsin--Education; Winnebago Indians--Education; Winnebago language--Texts
  - Doings at a meeting where the end of the war is proclaimed, 1959-07-12; 02-17; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:01; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 527.3.
    Black River Falls (Wis.); Winnebago Indians--History; Winnebago Indians--Wars; Winnebago language--Texts
  - The man who killed five opponents, 1959-07-12; 02-18; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:24; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 527.4.
  - The liar who was not believed by his people when once he spoke the truth, 1959-07-12; 02-19; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:51; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 527.5.
    Black River Falls (Wis.); Truthfulness and falsehood; Winnebago language--Texts
  - Fasting in olden days and the relative value of medicine herbs, 1959-07-12; 02-20; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:02; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 527.6.
    Black River Falls (Wis.); Fasting; Winnebago Indians--Medicine; Winnebago language--Texts
  - A night assault against a soldiers' camp foiled by an unseen negro guard, 1959-07-12; 02-21; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:04; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 527.7.
    African-American soldiers; Black River Falls (Wis.); Winnebago Indians--History; Winnebago Indians--Wars; Winnebago language--Texts
  - Fighting at dawn and Indians saved by a white man, 1959-07-12; 02-22; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:11; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 527.8.
  - The reborn man who became a drunkard and his experiences in an ambush near Log Bridge, 1959-07-13; 02-23; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:30; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 527.9.
    Alcoholics; Black River Falls (Wis.); Winnebago Indians--History; Winnebago language--Texts
  - A man who was building a fire knifed to death [1 of 3], 1959-07-13; 02-24; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:02; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 527.10, continued on 527.13. See Related Recording.
  - A peak-headed member of reborn triplets, 1959-07-13; 02-25; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:22; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 527.11.
    Black River Falls (Wis.); Triplets; Winnebago language--Texts
  - A Menominee visit to a chief's resort, 1959-07-13; 02-26; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:04; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 527.12.
    Black River Falls (Wis.); Menominee Indians; Winnebago Indians--History; Winnebago language--Texts
  - A man who was building a fire knifed to death [2 of 3], 1959-07-13; 02-27; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:36; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 527.13, a continuation of 527.10. See Related Recording.
  - How soldiers caught a black and a white boy, 1959-07-13; 02-28; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:26; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 528.1.
  - The Prophet speaks to the visiting Winnebago about medicine, 1959-07-13; 02-29; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:50; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 528.2, which is a continuation of 526.9. See Related Recording.
  - A man who was building a fire knifed to death [3 of 3], 1959-07-13; 02-30; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:40; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 528.3, which is a continuation of 527.10 and 527.13. See Related Recording.
  - Black Otter's sacrifice to Thunder when he was scared of war, 1959-07-13; 02-31; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:29; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 528.4.
    Black River Falls (Wis.); Sacrifice; Winnebago language--Texts
  - Burning of the old man's medicine bag, 1959-07-13; 02-32; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:20; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 528.5, which is a continuation of 526.11.
  - Prophecy about the end of the war and the behavior every man owes to himself, 1959-07-13; 02-33; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:00; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 528.6.
    Black River Falls (Wis.); Prophecies; Winnebago language--Texts
  - What women do when men go to war; The drunkard's self-reflections, 1959-07-13; 02-34; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:04; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 528.7.
    Alcoholics; Black River Falls (Wis.); Winnebago Indians--Wars; Winnebago language--Texts; Winnebago women; Women and war
  - The prophet speaks about the believers and disbelievers in his community, 1959-07-13; 02-35; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:08; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 528.8.
    Black River Falls (Wis.); Prophets; Winnebago Indians; Winnebago language--Texts
  - Women wash, clothe and feed a fasting man, 1959-07-13; 02-36; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:36; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 528.9.
    Black River Falls (Wis.); Fasting; Winnebago Indians--History; Winnebago Indians--Wars; Winnebago language--Texts; Winnebago women
  - Indian warfare and white strategy, 1959-07-13; 02-37; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:30; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 528.10.
  - The prophet speaks about the end of the war, 1959-07-13; 02-38; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:38; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 528.11.
    Black River Falls (Wis.); Prophecies; Prophets; Winnebago Indians--History; Winnebago Indians--Wars; Winnebago language--Texts
  - How the Winnebago and the Menominee lived together near the Great Lake [1 of 2], 1959-07-13; 02-39; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:26; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 528.12.
    Black River Falls (Wis.); Menominee Indians--History; Winnebago Indians--History; Winnebago language--Texts
  - How the Winnebago and the Menominee lived together near the Great Lake [2 of 2], 1959-07-13; 02-40; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:27; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
  - The prophet wants to teach all men of Good Will, 1959-07-13; 02-41; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:21; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 528.13.
    Black River Falls (Wis.); Prophets; Winnebago language--Texts
  - Forgiveness for a killer [1 of 4], 1959-07-20; 02-42; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:54; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 529.1.
  - Forgiveness for a killer [2 of 4], 1959-07-20; 02-43; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:38; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 529.2.
  - Forgiveness for a killer [3 of 4], 1959-07-20; 02-44; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:23; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 529.3.
  - The man on the lake, 1959-07-20; 02-45; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:25; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 529.4.
  - The prophet about war, 1959-07-20; 02-46; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:35; Fraenkel, Gerd; Stacy, Stella
    Text given in Winnebago only, with an English introduction by the collector. Recording contains a continuous background hum. Copy made by Gerd Fraenkel of an original tape held at the Archives of Languages of the World, Indiana University. This program is the original tape's program 529.5.